Guide to the Katherine S. Dreier Papers / Societe Anonyme Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Katherine S. Dreier: Photographs & Artwork, 1889-1951; Series V; 3; (9 boxes)
  Series V, Katherine S. Dreier: Photographs and Artwork, is organized into two subseries, Photographs and Artwork. The first subseries, Photographs, is organized into Katherine S. Dreier, Photographs of Artwork by Katherine S. Dreier, Dreier Family, Artists, Exhibitions, People, and Places. The second subseries, Artwork, is arranged alphabetically by artist.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Katherine S. Dreier
      - KSD's apartment at 135 Central Park West (New York, N.Y.). View of Marcel Duchamp's "Tu m'" over bookcases (3 prints), [ca. 1918] (Box 69, Folder 1775)
        See also: Oversize, box 119, folder 2825
      - China trip
        - KSD in garden, [ca. 1921-22] (Box 69, Folder 1776)
        - KSD in garden and dog with monkey on its back, [ca. 1921-22]
        - KSD in rickshaw in field (3 prints), [ca. 1921-22]
        - KSD in rickshaw in town, [ca. 1921-22]
        - KSD in buggy in town, [ca. 1921-22]
        - KSD with two unidentified people on sled on frozen river, [ca. 1921-22]
        - KSD with two unidentified women near monument?, [ca. 1921-22]
        - KSD in winter coat (double exposure), [ca. 1921-22]
        - At a meal (KSD in 2 of 3), [ca. 1921-22]
        - Unidentified man with family (4 scenes), [ca. 1921-22] (Box 69, Folder 1777)
        - Unidentified man alone (3 scenes), [ca. 1921-22]
        - Unidentified people (6 scenes), [ca. 1921-22]
        - Great Wall, [ca. 1921-22]
        - KSD seated, wearing Chinese silk dress and holding birdcage, [ca. 1921-22]
        - Copy prints from negative album of scenes in China, [ca. 1921-22] (Box 69, Folder 1778-1788)
        - Negative album of trip to China, [ca. 1921-22] (Box 70, Folder 1788a)
          Empty negative album, with captions.
      - Possibly with family members (three boys and one girl) (Box 70, Folder 1789)
      - Dressed in costume, with two men and one woman (studio portrait)
      - Seated in gondola in Venice with unidentified woman, 1902 Nov (Box 70, Folder 1790)
      - Standing in courtyard with "Mr. Whislow" and Mary E. Dreier, 1902 Nov
      - Seated on stone wall, "La Casa", 1903 Jan
      - Standing on ship with unidentified woman, 1903 Feb
      - Seated on ship with "Arthur Newbury" and "Mr. McDougall", 1903 Feb
      - Working on mural for Saint Paul's School (Garden City, N.Y.) (1 copy print), [1905] (Box 70, Folder 1791)
      - At easel, in smock, holding palette, proof, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1792)
      - In smock, holding palette, n.d.
      - Studio portrait, wearing coat, with muff, [ca. 1911-12]
      - Studio portrait, with knotted necklace, with hat, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1793)
      - Studio portrait, with knotted necklace, without hat (3 prints), n.d.
        By Herbert Mitchell.
      - Studio portrait (in portfolio), with knotted necklace and patterned dress (3 prints)
        See: Oversize, box 119, folders 2826-2828
      - Travel album containing photographs and postcards of scenes in Málaga, Granada, Seville, Guadalupe, and Toledo (Spain), 1929
        Includes following photographs of people: KSD with Kurt Schindler in Málaga; Marcel Duchamp leaning against edge of house in Granada; Marcel Duchamp standing in front of car in Granada; Marcel Duchamp, KSD, and Mrs. Thayer on steps of Cartuja de Granada; KSD with Marcel Duchamp standing in front of cathedral in Guadix; Marcel Duchamp standing in archway in Ronda (Málaga, Spain); KSD with Marcel Duchamp in Parque Maria Luisa, Seville (2 views); Marcel Duchamp in courtyard of museum in Seville; Marcel Duchamp and KSD standing in street in Toledo; Marcel Duchamp with unidentified woman at Puerta del Sol (Toledo), standing in front of chapel built by the Cid; "Our Packard car with its owner, Martinez" (Toledo).
        See: Oversize, box 122, folder 2866
      - With Kurt Schindler in Málaga (Spain), 1929 Feb 24
        See: Oversize, box 122, folder 2866 (p. 1)
      - With Marcel Duchamp in Parque Maria Luisa, Seville (Spain) (2 views), [1929]
        See: Oversize, box 122, folder 2866 (p. 31)
      - Group, probably for housewarming at the Haven (West Redding, Conn.): unidentified man, Ethel E. Dreier, H. Edward Dreier, KSD, Ted Shawn, unidentified woman, Mary E. Dreier, [1931 Oct 31?] (Box 70, Folder 1794)
      - For brochure, "Katherine S. Dreier: Lecturer and Painter" (Box 70, Folder 1795)
        Includes Marcel Duchamp, in trench coat, smoking pipe, on overcast day.
      - Sitting on porch steps with unidentified woman, Ethel E. Dreier, H. Edward Dreier, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1796)
      - With Ted Shawn, standing outside (2 views) (Box 70, Folder 1797)
      - Leaning on chair, with hands clasped (Box 70, Folder 1798)
      - Leaning on chair with elbow, n.d.
      - Wearing hat with feathers, close-up, front view, n.d.
      - Wearing hat with feathers, close-up, side view, n.d.
      - With Marcel Duchamp at Yale University Art Gallery exhibition, "Duchamp, Duchamp-Villon, Villon" (4 prints), [1945] (Box 70, Folder 1799)
      - Working on 40 Variations
        See: Oversize, box 125, folder 2869
      - Standing in hand elevator in Laurel Manor (Milford, Conn.), front view, [1948] (Box 70, Folder 1800)
      - Sitting in hand elevator in Laurel Manor (Milford, Conn.), front view, [1948]
      - Sitting in hand elevator in Laurel Manor (Milford, Conn.), side view, [1948]
      - With Koko on shoulder, [1948] (Box 70, Folder 1801)
      - With Koko (kissing KSD's chin) on shoulder (2 views, 2 prints), [1948]
      - Holding Koko on left hand (5 views, 5 prints), [1948]
      - Standing next to "The Cat" (Box 70, Folder 1802)
      - Standing next to "Zwei Welten" at Yale University Art Gallery exhibition (Box 70, Folder 1803)
      - Standing in middle of exhibition at Yale University Art Gallery
      - Reception at New Haven Lawn Club for dissolution of Société Anonyme
        - Gladys Seymour, Marcel Duchamp, Charles Seymour, KSD, Charles H. Sawyer (4 prints), [1950 Apr 30] (Box 70, Folder 1804)
        - Unidentified man, Charles Seymour, KSD, unidentified woman, unidentified man (9 prints), [1950 Apr 30] (Box 70, Folder 1805)
        - Dinner scene (8 prints), [1950 Apr 30] (Box 70, Folder 1806)
      - Standing in front of painting of church (Box 70, Folder 1807)
      - Haven (West Redding, Conn.)
        - Main entrance, front view (2 prints taped together), n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1808)
        - From main entrance looking toward Long Ridge Methodist Episcopal Church (West Redding, Conn.), n.d.
        - From main entrance looking toward garden, n.d.
        - Trellises in garden, n.d.
        - Fountain in garden, n.d.
        - Pond in garden
        - Stone wall in garden, n.d.
        - Brancusi's "Leda" in garden, n.d.
        - West porch, n.d.
        - West porch and old section of house
        - Inside hall, showing Brancusi's "Yellow Bird", n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1809)
        - Library, showing Marcel Duchamp's "Tu m'" and "Bride stripped bare by her bachelors, even" (4 prints, 2 proofs)
        - Library, close-up of Marcel Duchamp's "Tu m'" (2 versions, 5 prints), n.d.
        - Library, showing fireplace, n.d.
      - [Laurel Manor (Milford, Conn.). Dining area?] (Box 70, Folder 1810)
    - Photographs of Artwork by Katherine S. Dreier
      - 40 Variations. Four unidentified variations, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1811-1814)
        See also: Oversize, box 125, folder 2869
      - "Abstract Portrait of Marcel Duchamp" (5 prints, 1 proof), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1815)
      - "Abstract Portrait of Shawn" (3 prints, 1 proof), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1816)
        See also: Oversize, box 124, folder 2868
      - "Advent" (1 copy print), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1817)
      - "Albert Bridge, London" (Box 71, Folder 1818)
        See also: Oversize, box 123, folder 2867
      - "At a Stravinsky Program" (3 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1819)
      - "Atmospheric Variations"
        See: Box 71, folder 1850
      - "The Avenue, Nordwijk-Binnen" (1 print, 1 proof), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1820)
      - [Bridge, unidentified], n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1821)
      - "The Children's Party" (6 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1822)
      - "Cruel Prying" (3 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1823)
      - "Echoes of Bach" (2 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1824)
      - [Entrance to courtyard], n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1825)
      - "The Eternal Hills" (1 copy print), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1826)
        See also: Oversize, box 126, folder 2870
      - "Founding of Paterson" (4 prints, 2, proofs) (Box 71, Folder 1827)
        See also: Oversize, box 118, folder 2819
      - [Founding of Paterson. Study for?] (Box 71, Folder 1828)
      - "Frances Sylvia" (2 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1829)
      - "The Garden, Nordwijk-Binnen" (2 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1830)
      - [Garden with fountain], n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1831)
      - "Harvard Bridge, Boston", n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1832)
      - [Houses behind trees and water] (1 copy print) (Box 71, Folder 1833)
      - "Irritation" (3 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1834)
      - "Joy and Sorrow" (2 prints) (Box 71, Folder 1835)
      - "London in February" (2 prints) (Box 71, Folder 1836)
      - "Madame Gadeki as Aida", n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 118, folder 2820
      - "Maine" (5 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1837)
      - [Man, seated near fireplace, with cane] (2 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1838)
      - [Man, standing] (4 prints) (Box 71, Folder 1839)
      - [Man wearing bow tie] (2 prints), n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 118, folder 2821
        See: Oversize, box 124, folder 2868
      - "Mother and Child" (2 prints) (Box 71, Folder 1840)
      - "Mural Study of King Ferdinand" (3 prints) (Box 71, Folder 1841)
      - [Nude woman in outdoor scene], n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1842)
      - "Order Overcoming Chaos" (6 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1843)
      - "Peggy", n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1844)
      - "Portrait of Marcel Duchamp" (1 print, 1 proof), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1845)
      - [Saint Paul's School (Garden City, N.Y.). Mural for] (2 versions), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1846)
        See also: Box 70, folder 1791
      - "Sea Horses" (5 prints, 1 proof), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1847)
      - "Sketch for a Reredos", n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1848)
        See also: Oversize, box 118, folder 2822
      - "Song without Words" (2 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1849)
      - "Stonington Harbor" (5 prints, 4 postcards, 6 color proofs, 3 black and white proofs) (Box 71, Folder 1850)
      - [Street scene next to river scene], n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1851)
      - "Symphony in C Minor" (4 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1852)
      - "Symphony in C Minor" hanging in KSD's house, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1853)
      - "Twilight" (6 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1854)
      - "View from 37 Wall Street" (2 prints), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1855)
      - [Washington Irving High School. Mural for] (2 versions: 4 prints of one, 2 prints of other), 1928 (Box 71, Folder 1856)
        See also: Box 71, folder 1841
      - "The Wind" (Box 71, Folder 1857)
      - [Woman feeding chickens], n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 118, folder 2823
      - [Woman in cape with umbrella], n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1858)
      - [Woman playing musical instrument in water], n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1859)
      - [Woman reflected in mirror], n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1860)
        See also: Oversize, box 118, folder 2824
      - [Woman scattering dust in forest], n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1861)
      - [Woman, seated, with flowers and hat] (Box 72, Folder 1862)
      - [Woman wearing hat], n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1863)
      - "Zwei Welten" (4 prints, 2 proofs), n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1864)
      - Unidentified from Oversize, box 124, folder 2868 (2 different copy prints), n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1865)
      - Unidentified from Oversize, box 126, folder 2870 (4 prints; 3 prints), n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1866)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1867-1874)
      - Portfolio #1, 1906-15, n.d.
        Includes "Founding of Paterson"; "Harvard Bridge, Boston"; [Bridge, unidentified]; [Nude woman in outdoor scene]; [House near large tree]; [Woman holding jar?]; [Tree, alone in shadows]; "View of Chelsea"; "Oak Trees, Massachusetts"; [Large tree near smaller trees]; [Tree in field]; [Trees near building]; [Open landscape]; [Street scene next to river scene]; "London in February"; "Moonlight, Chelsea, London"; "Albert Bridge, London" (2 prints); "The Avenue, Nordwijk-Binnen"; [Houses behind trees and water]; "The Garden, Nordwijk-Binnen"; "Mother and Child"; [Queen attended by village?]; "Peggy"; [Washington Irving High School. Mural for] (4 prints); "Mural Study of King Ferdinand."
        See: Oversize, box 123, folder 2867
      - Portfolio #2, 1918-29, n.d.
        Includes "Bibi Lola"; [Woman reflected in mirror]; "Marcel Duchamp"; [Man wearing bow tie]; [Woman in cape with umbrella]; "Portrait of Bibi Lola" (2 prints); Unidentified; Unidentified; Unidentified; Unidentified (2 prints); [Man sitting in chair]; "Stonington Harbor"; "At a Stravinsky Program"; Unidentified; "Maine"; "Abstract Portrait of Shawn" (2 prints); Unidentified.
      - Portfolio #3, 1930-34, n.d.
        Includes "Zwei Welten"; Unidentified; "Order Overcoming Chaos"; "Cruel Prying"; "The Cat"; "Advent" (2 prints); "Echoes of Bach"; [KSD working on 40 Variations ]; [ 40 Variations. 13 unidentified variations].
      - Portfolio #4, 1934-35, n.d.
        Includes Unidentified (4 prints); "Irritation"; "The Blue Triangle" (3 prints); "The Eternal Hills"; "Song without Words" (2 prints); Unidentified; "Joy and Sorrow"; "Twilight."
        See: Oversize, box 126, folder 2870
    - Dreier Family
      - Dettmann, Kläre. With baby, [1938] (Box 73, Folder 1875)
      - Dreier, Mary E. Studio portrait, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1876)
      - Dreier, Theodore, Jr., 1929 Sep 20 (Box 73, Folder 1877)
      - "Dreier Offerman Park" (1 print, 1 proof), n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1878)
      - Maler, Invana, 1930 (Box 73, Folder 1879)
      - Maler, Willi
        - Little boy, standing under tree (Box 73, Folder 1880)
        - Portrait, front view, 1922
        - Portrait, side view, n.d.
        - Leaning against building, n.d.
    - Artists
      For more photographs of artists and their work, see also: Series X. Société Anonyme: Subject Files about Artists
      - Baumeister, Willi. With his artwork, 1947 Jul (Box 73, Folder 1881)
      - Beckerath, Willy von. Three of buildings and three of sculptures (Box 73, Folder 1882)
      - Bolotowsky, Ilya
        - "Times Square," (color slide), 1951 (Box 73, Folder 1883)
        - "Pompeian Red," (color slide), 1951
      - Burliuk, David and family in Hampton Bays, Long Island, 1947 Jul 22 (Box 73, Folder 1884)
      - Duchamp, Marcel (photographs of)
        - Seated, smoking, in KSD's apartment, 135 Central Park West, New York City (2 prints), [ca. 1918] (Box 73, Folder 1885)
        - Close-up of face (studio portrait), 1926 (Box 73, Folder 1886)
        - In gondola, in Venice, [1926 May] (Box 73, Folder 1887)
        - With bride, Lydia Levassor, [1927?] (Box 73, Folder 1888)
        - Leaning against edge of house in Granada (Spain), [1929]
          See: Oversize, box 122, folder 2866 (p. 4)
        - Standing in front of car in Granada (Spain), [1929]
        - With KSD and Mrs. Thayer on steps of Cartuja de Granada (Spain), [1929]
          See: Oversize, box 122, folder 2866 (p. 12)
        - With KSD, standing in front of cathedral in Guadix (Spain), [1929]
          See: Oversize, box 122, folder 2866 (p. 17)
        - Standing in archway in Ronda (Málaga, Spain), [1929]
          See: Oversize, box 122, folder 2866 (p. 22)
        - With KSD in Parque Maria Luisa, Seville, Spain (2 views), [1929]
        - In courtyard of museum in Seville (Spain), [1929]
          See: Oversize, box 122, folder 2866 (p. 32)
        - With KSD, standing in street in Toledo (Spain), [1929]
          See: Oversize, box 122, folder 2866 (p. 41)
        - With unidentified woman at Puerta del Sol (Toledo, Spain), standing in front of chapel built by the Cid, [1929]
          See: Oversize, box 122, folder 2866 (p. 47)
        - In trench coat, smoking pipe, on overcast day, n.d.
          See: Box 70, folder 1795
        - Seated on wooden chair in yard, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1889)
        - Standing, in trench coat and hat (Box 73, Folder 1890)
        - Seated on wire chair in park (2 prints), n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1891)
        - Seated on stone wall in yard, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1892)
        - Playing with dog in yard, n.d.
        - Seated next to unidentified standing man (with bird on shoulder) on patio in yard (2 prints) (Box 73, Folder 1893)
        - Seated, reading (with bird on shoulder), on patio in yard, n.d.
        - Seated, talking, on patio in yard, n.d.
        - Lighting cigarette, with bird on shoulder, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1894)
        - Seated, on porch railing, with hat off, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1895)
        - Seated, on porch railing, with hat on, n.d.
        - Leaning against porch railing, with hat on, n.d.
        - With unidentified man (studio portrait), n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1896)
      - Duchamp, Marcel (photographs of his artwork)
        - "3 Standard Stoppages" (2 views, 3 prints) (Box 73, Folder 1897)
        - "A regarder d'un oeil, de près, pendant presque une heure" (3 postcards) (Box 73, Folder 1898)
        - "Bride stripped bare by her bachelors, even." At International Exhibition of Modern Art (1926-1927: Brooklyn Museum), front view looking toward Fernand Léger's "Composition No. VII" (2 prints) (Box 73, Folder 1899)
          See also: Oversize, box 119, folder 2829
        - "Bride stripped bare by her bachelors, even." At International Exhibition of Modern Art (1926-1927: Brooklyn Museum), side view (2 versions), n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1900)
          Also shows Naum Gabo's "Column"; Constantin Brancusi's "Leda"; Joseph Stella's "Brooklyn Bridge"; Domela's "Composition" and Fernand Léger's "Composition No. VII."
        - "Bride stripped bare by her bachelors, even." After glass was broken (3 versions, 3 prints), n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1901)
        - "Bride stripped bare by her bachelors, even." After glass was broken (2 prints, positive and negative)
          See: Oversize, box 119, folder 2830
        - "Bride stripped bare by her bachelors, even." After glass was broken, at Haven (West Redding, Conn.) (5 views), n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1902)
        - "Fresh Widow", n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1903)
        - "Nude Descending a Staircase" (2 prints: 1 color) (Box 73, Folder 1904)
        - "Rotary Glass Plates." Still (1 print, 3 proofs; in motion (3 proofs), n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1905)
        - "Sieste éternelle", n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1906)
        - [Stool with Christmas tree], n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1907)
        - Unidentified artwork, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1908)
      - Ernst, Max. Paintings, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1909)
      - Harris, Lawren. Portrait, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1910)
      - Jones, David Taylor. Marble abstraction, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1911)
      - Levitan, Jack and Idee Fulkerson. Sculpture and painting, [1951] (Box 73, Folder 1912)
        Includes one portrait of Levitan sculpting.
      - Lissitzky, El and family (5 views) (Box 73, Folder 1913)
      - Lozowick, Louis. Portrait, close-up of face, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1914)
      - Molzahn, Johannes. Artwork (6 works, 6 prints), 1939 (Box 73, Folder 1915)
      - Pannaggi, Ivo. Children: Kora, Marco, Tito (3 prints), 1947 (Box 73, Folder 1916)
      - Rees, Adya van. Two paintings: "God Warns" and "Le sablier" (Box 73, Folder 1917)
      - Sargent, John Singer and his sister as children (5 prints) (Box 73, Folder 1918)
        Photograph (by John D. Schiff) of a photograph.
        See also: Box 31, folder 914 (1948 Mar 9)
      - Schwitters, Kurt
        - With Edith Thomas on mountainside picnic, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1919)
        - Relief Construction, n.d.
        - "Cylinders Farm. Part of the estate where the barn is standing"
      - Shirlaw, Walter. "In Church", n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1920)
      - Vasari, P. R. Portrait, 1922 Nov 14 (Box 73, Folder 1921)
        Inscribed to KSD.
    - Exhibitions
      - Anderson Galleries. "Fernand Léger," 1925 Nov 16-28
        - View of exhibition (3 prints), n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1922)
        - 11 paintings (15 prints, 2 proofs), n.d.
      - [Bennington College. "4 Painters," 1936 Oct 15-Nov 9?]. 3 views of exhibition, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1923)
      - Competition for Sculpture in Plexiglas. Five winning designs, [1939] (Box 74, Folder 1924)
      - Cooperative Mural Workshops. Seven murals, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1925)
      - [George Walter Vincent Smith Art Museum]
        - Leon Carroll Memorial Exhibition?] (5 prints, 3 views), n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1926)
        - "Some New Forms of Beauty," 1940 Jan 4-Feb 4?] (12 views), n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1927)
      - International Exhibition of Modern Art (1926-1927: Brooklyn Museum)
        - (5 views of exhibition, 11 prints), n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1928)
          See also: Box 73, folder 1899
        - Artwork exhibited, n.d.
          Includes Brancusi, Constantin. "Miss Pogany"; Duchamp, Marcel. "Nude Descending a Staircase"; [Lehmbruck, Wilhelm. "Standing Woman"?]; Villon, Jacques. ["La Femme au piano"]; Unidentified.
          See: Oversize, box 119, folder 2831
      - Sesqui-Centennial International Exposition
        - Painting by Lawren Harris from exhibition catalog, [1926] (Box 74, Folder 1929)
        - 4 views of exhibition rooms (6 prints), [1926]
      - Society of Independent Artists (New York, N.Y.). Exhibition at Grand Central Palace, [1917] (Box 74, Folder 1930)
    - People
      - Burliuk, Nicholas
        - Painting, 1947 Aug (Box 74, Folder 1931)
        - His daughter, Mary-Claire, 1947 Jun
      - Cheatham, Kitty, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1932)
        Inscribed to KSD, 1935 Apr 26.
      - Dearstyne, Howard
        - With family, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1933)
        - View of Albany, n.d.
      - Gabo, Miriam. With dog, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1934)
      - Gogh, Elisabeth du Quesne van
        - Studio portrait, [1918 Oct 20?] (Box 74, Folder 1935)
        - Postcard portrait, 1927 May
      - [Hartt, Frederick?]. Children with nuns (3 views), n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1936)
      - Hess, Inez Elizabeth. With Dr. Wells, [1946 May] (Box 74, Folder 1937)
      - Lynn, Carol
        - KSD's lithograph used in Lynn's dance, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1938)
        - Scene from Lynn's dance using KSD's lithograph, n.d.
      - Moholy-Nagy, Lucia. Sixth International Congress for Drawing, Art Education, and Applied Arts (Prague), 1928 Aug (Box 74, Folder 1939)
        Contains: "Dr. A. Specker"; "Mr. Einstein"; "Max Merz"; "Prof. Mokry, Mr. Albers"; "Mr. Royal B. Farnum"; "An Asiatic group"; "Garden Party"; "Mr. Mararyk, President of the Czechoslavakian Republique and the Delegates of the Nations."
      - Mumaw, Barton. Dance poses
        - Mid-air split, 1936 Jun (Box 74, Folder 1940)
        - As Native American, kneeling, n.d.
        - As Native American, on one foot, n.d.
        - In feather headdress, in deep plié
      - Rebay, Hilla
        - With two terriers, 1948 (Box 74, Folder 1941)
        - With three terriers, n.d.
        - Guggenheim, Solomon R., Hilla Rebay, and Frank Lloyd Wright
        - Guggenheim, Solomon R. and unidentified couple in Rebay's garden, 1948 May
        - Three views of Rebay's living room, n.d.
        - Three landscapes, possibly southwestern United States
      - Schwitters, Eve. At Christmas, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1942)
      - Shawn, Ted
        - Seated in striped chair, far away, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1943)
        - Seated in striped chair, upclose, n.d.